SIEGFRED SAMSON

ABUJA | LAGOS NIGERIA / (+234) 803 619 2916

siegfred@siegfredsamson.com | samsonsiegfred.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/siegfred/ | https://github.com/siegfred14

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a people-friendly individual who is decision and result oriented, coachable and with good communication skills. As an avid learner, I am comfortably a team player who is largely attracted by the effects of technology on daily affairs, especially as it relates to business, health, community development and human advancement. In addition to my skills and experience in web development, software engineering, sales and marketing, computer engineering, finance and banking, I am also bilingual. I am open to learning new methods to improve myself, my organization and environment by working in your company.

HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICATIONS

- Over 7 years in web development, with experience in both frontend and backend development.
- 2 years in computer engineering, working as a Systems Support Engineer.
- Fluent in English and French, with certified qualifications CLB 8 in International English Language
 Testing System (IELTS) and niveau B2 in Diplôme d'Etudes en Langue Française (DELF).
- Completed degree in Computer Science.
- Versatile in interpersonal relationships and willing to learn.

EXPERTISES

- Application Information Gathering
- Mark Up and Stylesheet Development
- Coding and debugging
- Database and server development
- API development
- Hosting and Deployment
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Public Speaking and problem-solving

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer (Web)

Code Clan Nigeria - Nigeria

January 2020 - Present

- Working with clients to understand, receive and document their requirements
- Drawing up of Web site replica and graphic illustrations for pre-visualization of intended product
- Creation of Web site plan and deciding on appropriate hardware and software demands

- Integrating data from several back-end web services, APIs and databases
- Information gathering, sorting and assembly for inclusion and for decision on the design, appearance, layout and flow of the Web site
- Developing, modifying and optimizing content and page loading time for the internet site using an array of programs, images, database and animations
- Planning and writing well-designed, testable, efficient code by employing web development best practices
- Executing tests and dispatching security and quality control activities
- Ensuring cross browser compatibility of new features
- Collaborating with other developers to research and evaluate modern interactive media software products
- Keeping up to date with emerging technologies and industry trends, and applying them to operations and activities.

Backend Developer (Web) Kwatri Digital Press - Abuja, Feb 2015 – Dec 2019 Nigeria

- Engaged with stakeholders to understand, develop and document the technical demands of their projected Web site
- Executed the preparation of models to illustrate envisaged Web site
- Developed the hierarchical structure of intended Web site pages to decide on hardware and software requirement and specifications
- Contributed design solutions to address critical issues and complex problems
- Collaborated with front end developers to create and publish content, basic Web site layout and
 user interfaces for Web sites and the office intranet
- Worked with the development team to maintain the necessary security surrounding access to Internet site
- Employed frameworks to build server-side software and integrate Application Programming Interfaces
- Carried out database creation, integration and management
- Wrote, transformed, integrated and tested code, to achieve intended structure, design and functionality of Web site

- Ensured adaptability and consistency of new features across browsers
- Performed tests and employed quality controls to ensure Web site functionality is maintained
- Created and maintained Web site documentation
- Executed the maintenance, expansion, and scaling of Web site
- Supervised a team of designers, front end and backend developers to develop Web site graphics,
 versatility and connectivity
- Stayed abreast with emerging technologies in the Web development industry to deliver state-ofthe-art Web site products.

EDUCATION	
La langue Francaise Niveau A1 à B2 Institut Francais Nigeria	Feb 2021 - Dec 2021
Bachelor of Science, Computer Science University of Abuja, Nigeria	Oct 2004 - Jan 2009
CERTIFICATES	
Crisis Management London School of Public Relations Limited – London, UK	Apr 2022
International Team Building and Leadership Convention Alliance in Motion Global Inc. – Manila, Philippines	May 2019
Interconnecting Cisco Networking Devices (CCNA 640 – 802) HiiT - Lagos, Nigeria	Apr 2009